Guide to the Native American subject vertical file [ca.1850-2000.]
Native American subject vertical file
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Native American subject vertical file [ca.1850-2000.]
9205
Huntington Free Library.
129 cubic ft.
Printed materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
This collection contains ephemera covering a broad variety of topics relating to Native Americans.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection contains ephemera covering a broad variety of topics. Brochures, correspondence, programs from events, theses manuscripts, monographs, maps, music, photographs, plays, postcards, reprints, publications, small books, and government bills and statements, are included organized by subject. Collection was established as a catch all for items pertaining to Indians that were collected by staff of the Huntington Free Library. Collection contains a vast range of reference material, that covers anthropology, archaeology, culture, education, politics, and many other Native American topics. Collection also provides history on various locations and cities. Many unique, author signed and annotated, and privately printed items. In some cases the collection contains information about the aquisition of objects that now may reside at the National Museum of the American Indian.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Huntington Free Library.; Huntington Free Library.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of Mexico.; Indians of South America.; Indians of North America -- Education.; Indians of North America -- Exhibitions.; Indians of North America -- Folklore.; Indians of North America -- Government relations.; Indians of North America -- Land tenure.; Indians of North America -- Languages.; Indians of North America -- Missions.; Abenaki Indians.; Cherokee Indians.; Dakota Indians.; Hopi Indians.; Iroquois Indians.; Mohawk Indians.; Navajo Indians.; Puelbo Indians.; Seminole Indians.; Zuni Indians.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Only a fraction of the actual subject headings are given in the record; see the guide for the complete listing.
Forms part of the Native American Collection. (NAC)
See also the Native American artist vertical file, #9241, Native American biography vertical file, #9242, and Native American publications vertical file, #9246.
CONTAINER LIST
- Abnaki Indians (Algonquian) - See also Folklore - Abnaki, Language Abnaki (Box 1)
- Abnaki Indians - Articles, Corres. (Box 1)
- Academics - American Anthropological Association (Box 1)
- Academics - American Ethnological Society (Box 1)
- Academics - American Folklore Society (Box 1)
- Academics - American Geographical Society (Box 1)
- Academics - American Indian Ethnohistoric Conference (Box 1)
- Academics - American Numismatic Society (Box 1)
- Academics - American Philosophical Society (Box 1)
- Academics - Amerind Foundation (Box 1)
  Not received
- Academics - Archaeological Institute of America - See also Bot Archeology (Brown) (Box 1)
- Academics - Archaeological Institute of America - School of American Research (Box 1)
- Academics - Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 1)
- Academics - California University (Box 1)
- Academics - Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 1)
- Academics - Champlain Society (Box 1)
- Academics - Cortes Society (Box 1)
- Academics - Eastern States Archaeological Federation (Box 1)
- Academics - Explorers Club (Box 1)
- Academics - Florida State Historical Society, Deland, Florida (Box 1)
- Academics - Hispanic Society of America (Box 1)
- Academics - Instituto, Indigenista Interamericano (Box 1)
- Academics - International Council of Museums (Box 1)
- Academics - International Congress of Americanists (Box 1)
- Academics - International Congress of Americanists - Articles, corres. (Box 1)
- Academics - Massachusetts historical Society (Box 1)
- Academics - Maya, Society (Box 1)
- Academics - National Research Council (Box 1)
- Academics - New Mexico University (Box 1)
- Academics - New York Historical Society (Box 1)
- Academics - New York State Archaeological Association (Box 1)
- Academics - Organization of American Historians (Box 1)
- Academics - Quivira, Society (Box 2)
- Academics - Society for American Archaeology (Box 2)
- Academics - Society for Ethnomusicology (Box 2)
- Academics - Texas Archaeological Society (Box 2)
- Academics - Tulane University Middle American Research Institute - See also Biog - Gates, Wm. (Box 2)
- Academics - U. S. Bureau of American Ethnology (Box 2)
- Academics - Viking Fund Inc. (Box 2)
- Academics - Wisconsin State Historical Society (Box 2)
- Academics and Learned Societies - See also Pamphlet box, expeditions, libraries, museums (Box 2)
- Academics and Learned Societies 2 (Box 2)
- Academics and Learned Societies - Articles & Corres. (Box 2)
- Academics and Learned Societies - Amerind Foundation (Box 2)
- Acculturation and culture contact (Box 2)
- Achomawi & Atsugewi Indians (Pit River and Hat Creek) See also Shasta Indians (Box 2)
- Actors, Actresses (Box 2)
- Adoption (Box 2)
- Africa (Box 2)
- African - Indian relations (Box 2)
- Aged (Box 2)
- Agriculture (i.e. production of plants, etc.) - 3 folders - See also Pamphlet box, Ethnobotany (Box 3)
- Agriculture 2 (Box 3)
- Agriculture 3 (Box 3)
- Agriculture (i.e. production of plants, etc.) - Articles & Corres. (Box 3)
- Aid to Indians (Box 133)
- Alabama - Antiquities - See also Pamphlet box (Box 3)
- Alabama - Antiquities - 2 (Box 3)
- Alabama - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 3)
- Alabama - Indians (Box 3)
- Alaculuf Indians (Tierra del Fuego) - See also languages, Alacalufan (Box 3)
- Alaska - See also Pamphlet box (Box 3)
- Alaska 2 (Box 3)
- Alaska - Articles & Corres. (Box 3)
- Alaska - Antiquities - See also Pamphlet box (Box 4)
- Alaska - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Alaska - Eskimo - See also Pamphlet box (Box 4)
- Alaska - Eskimo - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Alaska - History - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Alaska - Indians - See also Missions - Alaska (Box 4)
- Alaska - Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Alaska - Indians-Legal documents (Box 4)
- Alaska-Native Claims (Box 4)
- Alaska-Native Peoples (Box 4)
- Alberta (Box 4)
- Alcoholism (Box 4)
- Aleutian Islands - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Aleuts (Box 4)
- Aleuts - Articles & Corres. (Box 4)
- Algonkin Indians (Canadian Tribes) (Box 5)
- Algonquian Indians (linguistic family) (Box 5)
- Alibamu Indians (Muskhogean) - See also folklore Alibamu (Box 5)
- Alibamu Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 5)
- Amazon - Indians (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - See also Biography - Colombo, Chritoforo, Vasquez de Coronado. (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - Norse 1 - See also pamphlet box (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - Norse 2 (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - Norse - Articles & Corres. (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - Pre - Columbian (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - Pre - Columbian - Articles & Corres. (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - The West - See also Pamphlet Box - Expeditions Lewis & Clark (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - The West - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 5)
- America - Discovery and Exploration - The West - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 5)
- American Archaeology - Bulletin of the Society for (Box 5)
- American Indian Day (Box 6)
- American Indian Day - Articles & Corres. (Box 6)
- American Indian Defense Society (Box 6)
- American Indian Librarians (Box 133)
- American Indian Movement (Box 6)
- American Indian Religion Act (Box 6)
- American Indian Policy Review Commission (Box 133)
- American Indians in the Professions (Box 133)
- Anasazi (Box 132)
- Andes - Antiquities (Box 6)
- Animals - Bibliography (Box 6)
- Animals - Birds (Box 6)
- Animals - Bison (Box 6)
- Animals - Bison - Articles & Corres. (Box 6)
- Animals - Dogs (Box 6)
- Animals - Horses (Box 6)
- Animals - Mexico, Central America, South America (Box 6)
- Animals - North America (Box 6)
- Animals - Reindeer (Box 6)
- Animals - Reptiles (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Indians (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. 1 (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. 2 (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. 3 (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 6)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Instructions, methods, etc. - Articles & Corres. 3 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 1 - See also Mummies (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 2 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 3 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 4 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 5 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 6 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 7 (Box 7)
- Anthropology - Physical 8 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical 9 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 3 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 4 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 5 (Box 8)
- Anthropology - Physical - Articles & Corres. 6 (Box 8)
- Antiquities (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Fraudulent 1 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Fraudulent 2 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Fraudulent - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Fraudulent - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Legislation (Box 8)
- Antiquities - Preservation (Box 8)
- Antiquities - U.S. (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians 1 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians 2 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians 3 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians 4 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians 5 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians - Articles & Corres. 3 (Box 9)
- Antiquity and origin of Indians - Articles & Corres. 4 (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - Antiquities (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - Articles Corres. (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - Ethnology (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - History (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - Legal Articles (Box 9)
- Apache Indians - San Carlos (Box 10)
- Apalai Indians (Box 10)
- Arapaho Indians (Algonquian) See also Folklore - Arapaho Language - Arapaho (Box 10)
- Arapaho Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 10)
- Araucanian Indians (Box 10)
- Araucanian Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 10)
- Arawak Indians (South America) See also Languages - Arawakan (Box 10)
- Arawak Indians (South America) - Articles & Corres. (Box 10)
- Archaeoastronomy (Box 10)
- Archaeological Survey (Box 133)
  Department of the Army
- Archaeology 1 (Box 10)
- Archaeology 2 (Box 10)
- Archaeology - Articles & Corres. (Box 10)
- Archaeology, instruction, methods, etc. (Box 10)
- Archaeology, instruction, methods, etc. - Articles & Corres. (Box 10)
- Archaeology Schools (Box 10)
- Architects and Engineers (Box 133)
- Architecture (Box 10)
- Archives (Box 10)
- Archives and manuscripts (Box 10)
- Arda (Negroes) (Brazil) (Box 10)
- Argentina - See also Tierra del Fuego (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities 1 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities 2 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities 3 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Central 1 - (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Central 2 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Central 3 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Central - Articles & Corres. 1 Santiago del Estero, Santa Fe, Cordoba, San Luis, Crias (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Central - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - East 1 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - East 2 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - East 3 (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - East - Articles & Corres - Entre Rios, Buenos Aires (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northeast - Fotmosa, Corrientes, Misiones (Box 11)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 1 - Jujuy, Satta, Los Andes, Tucuman, Catamarca, La Roja (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 2 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 3 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 4 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 5 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 6 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest 7 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest - Articles & Corres. 1 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Northwest - Articles & Corres. 2 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - Patagonia (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - South 1 - Argentine Patagonia, temtones of La Pampa, Rio Negro, Chubut, Santa Cruz - See also Tierra del Fuego (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - South 2 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - South 3 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - South - Articles & Corres. (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - West 1 - San Juan, Mendoza, Neuquen (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - West 2 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - West 3 (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - West - Articles & Corres. (Box 12)
- Argentina - Antiquities - History (Box 12)
- Argentina Indians 1 (Box 12)
- Argentina Indians 2 (Box 13)
- Argentina Indians 3 (Box 13)
- Argentina Indians 4 (Box 13)
- Argentina Indians 5 (Box 13)
- Argentina Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 13)
- Argentina Indians - History (Box 13)
- Arikara Indians (Box 13)
- Arikara Indians - Field notes and publications by Melvin R. Gilmore (Box 13)
- Arizona (Box 13)
- Arizona - Bibliographies (Box 13)
- Arizona - History (Box 13)
- Arizona - Natural Resources (Box 13)
- Arizona - Antiquities 1 (Box 13)
- Arizona - Antiquities 2 (Box 13)
- Arizona - Antiquities 3 (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities 4 (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities 5 (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities 6 (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities 7 (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Articles & Corres. (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Casa Grande (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Climate, Flora & Fauna (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Montezuma's Well & Castle (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Pottery (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Prehistoric Canals (Box 14)
- Arizona - Antiquities - Texas Canyon (Box 15)
- Arizona Indians 1 (Box 15)
- Arizona Indians 2 (Box 15)
- Arizona Indians - Articles & Corres. (Box 15)
- Arizona Indians - Legislation (Box 15)
- Arizona Indians - Tribal Directories (Box 15)
- Arkansas Indians (Box 15)
- Arkansas Indians - Antiquities (Box 15)
- Art 1 (Box 15)
- Art 2 (Box 133)
- Art - Oversize (Box 131)
- Art - Articles & Corres. (Box 15)
- Art - Canada (Box 15)
- Art - Central America (Box 15)
- Art - Design and Application (Box 15)
- Art - Education and History (Box 15)
- Art - Eskimos (Box 16)
- Art - Fakes (Box 16)
- Art - Legislation (Box 16)
- Art - South America (Box 16)
- Art - Theft and Problems (Box 16)
- Arts and Crafts (Box 132)
- Assimilation (Box 16)
- Assiniboine Indians (Siouan) (Box 16)
- Associations - A (Box 16)
- Associations - Administration for Native Americans (Box 16)
- Associations - Alaska Indian Art (Box 16)
- Associations - Alaska Native Brotherhood (Box 16)
- Associations - Alaska Native Foundation (Box 16)
- Associations - Alaska Native Sisterhood (Box 16)
- Associations - American Anthropological Association (Box 16)
- Associations - American Bible Society (Box 16)
- Associations - American Ethnological Society (Box 16)
- Associations - American Folklore Society (Box 16)
- Associations - American Friends Service Committee (Box 16)
- Association - American Indian Against Desecration (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian/Alaska Native Nurses Association Inc. (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Archaeological Institute - see also - Association - Institute for American Indian Studies (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Association [contains documents signed by Chiefs Running Bear and White Eagle] (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Chicago Conference (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian College Fund (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Community House 1 (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Community House 2 (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Community House - 1970 - 1979 (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Community House - 1980 - 1989 (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Cultural Exchange (Box 16)
- Associations - American Indian Cultural Research Center Blue Cloud Abbey (SD) (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Day (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Development, Inc. (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Federation (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Foundation (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Heritage Foundation (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Historical Association (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Law Center (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Lawyer Training Program (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian League (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Liberation Crusade, Inc (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Movement (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian National Bank (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Physicians, Inc. (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Registry (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Research and Resource Institute (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Ritual Object Repatriation Foundation (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Science and Engineering Society (Box 17)
- Associations - American Indian Theater Company of Oklahoma (Box 17)
- Associations - American Research Libraries (Box 17)
- Associations - Americans for Indian Opportunity (Box 17)
- Associations - Arrow (Box 17)
- Associations - Artists Hopid (Box 17)
- Associations - Artistas Indigenas (Box 17)
- Associations - Associated Committee (Box 17)
- Associations - Association of American Indian Culture (Box 17)
- Associations - Association of American Indian Physicians (Box 17)
- Associations - Associations on American Indian Affairs, Inc. (Box 17)
- Associations - Associations on American Indian Affairs, Inc. 1936-1959 (Box 17)
- Associations - Associations on American Indian Affairs, Inc. 1960-to date (Box 17)
- Associations - B (Box 17)
- Associations - Bear Tribe (Box 17)
- Associations - Biitish Columbia Indian Language Project Society (Box 17)
- Associations - Bronx County Historical Society (Box 17)
- Associations - Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions (Box 17)
- Associations - Bureau of Indian Affairs (Box 17)
- Associations - C (Box 17)
- Associations - Canadian Association in Support of the Native Peoples (Box 17)
- Associations - Canadian Ethnic Studies Associations (Box 17)
- Associations - Capistrano Trading Post (Box 17)
- Associations - Carnegie (Box 17)
- Associations - Center for American Archaeology (Box 17)
- Associations - Center for Applied Linguistics (Box 17)
- Associations - Center for Inter - American Relations (Box 17)
- Associations - Circle of Red Nations (Box 17)
- Associations - Connecticut Friends of Indians (Box 18)
- Associations - Contemporary American Indian Art Project (Box 18)
- Associations - Corn Maya (Box 18)
- Associations - Council of California Indians, Inc. (Box 18)
- Associations - Council of Energy Resource Tribes (Box 18)
- Associations - D (Box 18)
- Associations - Dartmouth (Box 18)
- Associations - Daughters of the American Revolution (Box 18)
- Associations - Department of Culture and Youth (Box 18)
- Associations - E (Box 18)
- Associations - Earthwatch (Box 18)
- Associations - Eastern Associations on Indian Affairs (Box 18)
- Associations - Eastern States (Box 18)
- Associations - ERIC (Box 18)
- Associations - Exposition of Indian Tribal Arts (Box 18)
- Associations - F (Box 18)
- Associations - Florida Governors Council on Indian Affairs (Box 18)
- Associations - Foundation for Latin American Research (Box 18)
- Associations - Foundation of North American Indian Culture (Box 18)
- Associations - Futures for Children (Box 18)
- Associations - G (Box 18)
- Associations - General (Box 18)
- Associations - General Federation of Women’s Clubs, Indian Welfare Division (Box 18)
- Associations - Gesellschaft Fur Bedrohte Volker (Box 18)
- Associations - Grupo Aymara (Box 18)
- Associations - H (Box 18)
- Associations - Hopi Center for Human Services (Box 18)
- Associations - Human Area Relations Files (Box 18)
- Associations - I (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Arts and Crafts Board (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Arts Fund (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Confederation of America (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Council Fire (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian League of the Americas (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Pueblo Cultural Center (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Research and Resource Institute (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Rights Associations (Box 18)
- Associations - Indian Welfare League (Box 18)
- Associations - Institute for American Indian Studies - see - also - Associations - American Indian Archaeological Institute (Box 18)
- Associations - Institute for Development of Indian Law (Box 18)
- Associations - Institute of American Arts (Box 18)
- Associations - Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture (Box 18)
- Associations - Institute of the American West (Box 18)
- Associations - Inter - American Indian Institute (Box 19)
- Associations - International Congress of Americanists (Box 19)
- Associations - International Indian Treaty Council (Box 19)
- Associations - Interstate Congress for Equal Rights and Responsibilities (Box 19)
- Association - Inter - Tribal Indian Ceremonial Association (Box 19)
- Associations - Inuit Circompolar Conference (Box 19)
- Associations - J (Box 19)
- Associations - K (Box 19)
- Associations - L (Box 19)
- Associations - Lake Mohonk Indian Conference (Box 19)
- Associations - Lenni Lenape (Box 19)
- Associations - Los Angeles Indian Center (Box 19)
- Associations - Lumbee (Box 19)
- Associations - M (Box 19)
- Associations - Manitoba Record Society (Box 19)
- Associations - METRO (Box 19)
- Associations - Mohawk Valley Project (Box 19)
- Associations - N (Box 19)
- Associations - National Advisory Council on Indian Education (Box 19)
- Associations - National Association for Native American Children of Alcoholics (Box 19)
- Associations - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box 19)
- Associations - National Congress of American Indians 1 (Box 19)
- Associations - National Congress of American Indians 2 (Box 19)
- Associations - National Congress of American Indians 3 (Box 19)
- Association - National Council of American Indian (Box 19)
- Associations - National Educational Associations (Box 19)
- Associations - National Gallery of the American Indian (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Association (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Bilingual Center (Box 19)
- Association - National Indian Child Welfare Association (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Council on Aging Inc. (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Education Association (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Employment Center (Box 19)
- Associations - National Indian Youth Council (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Art Studies Assoc. (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Education Program (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Journalists Association (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Lobby (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Public Broadcasting Consortium (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Rehabilitation Association (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Research Information Service (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Rights Fund (Box 19)
- Associations - Native American Treaty Rights Organization (Box 20)
- Associations - Native Americans for a Clean Environment (Box 20)
- Associations - Native Indian/Inuit Photographer's Association (Box 20)